Lindsey Lee Pregent

Brooklyn, New York 11214 | lindsey.pregent@gmail.com

Portfolio | Github | LinkedIn | Medium

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Experience in Ruby and JavaScript-based programming languages with a background in client services. Confident Bootcamp grad who knows how to work well under pressure and learn quickly. Flexible and agile with a zest for problem-solving and working with people. Understands the client's perspective and excitedly translates that into a positive experience. Proven ability to lead, collaborate and innovate. Passion for Social Justice, equity, animal rescue, and music. Motivated to continue advancing new skillset in the wide world of tech and continue helping people.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby on Rails, React, Javascript, SQLite, CSS, HTML, Ruby Geocoder, Bootstrap, Postgres, Postman, Mapbox, EmailJS

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Community Cat Catalog - Github | Demo

Catalog and track stray cats in your community!

- Utilized React-Map-GL and Ruby-Geocoder to plot dynamic markers on a map.
- Worked with Ruby-on-Rails and Postgres to create a comprehensive Cat database.
- Used Bcrypt to allow users to log in and track their own cats.

AnotherTreasure - Github

Connecting charitable organizations with the community for used clothing and household donations.

- Utilized React Map-GL to display markers on a map interface.
- Worked with Email.JS for direct emails from users to organizations
- Created a form for users to add items to the database and edit those items.

TarotReader - Github | Demo

Step right in for your virtual tarot reading and experience.

- Developed an extensive JSON API with tarot card details.
- Implemented RESTful routing in order to display unique pages for each tarot card.
- Created several interactive features through a combination of CSS and JS.

EXPERIENCE

Lawyers For Children New York, NY Administrative Assistant 08/2012 - 12/2021

Data entry and upkeep via an electronic case management platform.

• Maintained the office and inventory for a positive client and staff experience.

Starbucks
New York, NY
Barista
03/2010 - 10/2012

• Provided excellent customer service, staff training, and sales in a fast-paced environment.

Brooklyn Animal ActionVolunteer

Brooklyn, NY

08/2020 - Current

• TNR (Trap-Neuter-Return) Certified. Cat Rescuer, Cat Foster/Socializer, and Community Liaison.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

New York, NY
Certificate in Software Engineering. Full Stack Web Development, Ruby/React

01/2022 - 04/2022

Brooklyn College
Coursework Completed towards Degree in Liberal Arts

Brooklyn, NY
08/2007 - 12/2007

Curtis High School Staten Island, NY National Honor Society 06/2007